Hey everybody, in this content
video, we're going to talk
briefly about section 7.6 of
your textbook, and we will do a
quick demo of some of the NumPy
versus built-in Python list.
What was I saying? Like the
differences between them and how
much faster they actually
are. So I'm not going to code
anything live for you, but we
do have this kind of demo speed
test that you can look at. So
I've got three libraries I'm
importing, NumPy, random, and
time. Time is a good library.
There's a lot of great functions
that you can use in there.
I like time because it will
print out the time that
you are running your code
as. Like if I said time.now,
it would print out the exact
time that right now is.
Time.time just gives us
kind of like the same
thing this time, the
current time that it's at.
So what we're going to
do is we're going to fill
a Python list with, let's
see, how many is this?
A million random numbers
between one and 50.
and then we will print out
how long that takes and
then we're going to do the
same thing with a numpy array
and um see how much faster
it is so here we go oh
that's the numpy zeros I was like
why did I print out a random list
okay so I don't know if you guys can
see this but the python list took
about 0.8 seconds but the numpy
array took a fraction of the time
it's literally less than half of
the time. It took 0.28 of a second,
which is, like I said, a fraction of
that time. To get through a million
iterations, it took literally
less than half the time. So if you
think about how this scales, right,
like we're not just talking about
like tiny examples that we're just
doing in our little code base in
our kitchen while we're eating
spaghetti, but we're talking about like
really big applications of this
concept, right? Like if I'm working
on a database or if I'm working
with um cloud computing or something
like really really big with a lot
and like a lot of data um you're
going to start wanting to prioritize
things that are going to run faster
and use less memory because in the
real world when you are running
code the longer it's taking to run
the longer it's taking to compile
kind of means that that's more
money that's literally being spent
or resources that are being depleted
and so if you can run your code
faster and more efficiently then
And that's going to be a good thing.
So this is kind of like the
power of NumPy, if you will.
So that's all for this content
video. Thanks for watching.